睁开你的眼睛
Open your eyes.
这就是我们魔法的来源？
This is where our magic comes from?
Mm-hmm.
这根蜡烛里有我们家的奇迹
This candle holds the miracle given to our family.
我们怎么获得奇迹的？
How did we get a miracle?
很久以前
Long ago...
我的三个宝宝刚出生
When my three babies had just been born...
我和你的佩德罗阿公被迫逃离我们家
Your abuelo Pedro and I were forced to flee our home.
虽然很多人加入我们
And though many joined us...
希望找到新的家园
Hoping to find a new home...
我们却碰上了危险
We could not escape the dangers...
你阿公就这么走了
And your abuelo was lost.
但在最绝望的时候
But in our darkest moment...
我们获得了一个奇迹
We were given a miracle.
这根蜡烛成了永不熄灭的神奇火焰
The candle became a magical flame that could never go out.
赐给我们一个可以生活的避难所
And it blessed us with a refuge in which to live.
一个充满奇迹的地方
A place of wonder.
一个非凡之地
An encanto.
非凡之地
这个奇迹继续成长
The miracle grew.
而我们的房子
And our house...
我们的家
Our casita itself...
活了起来，保护我们
Came alive to shelter us.
当我的孩子长大
When my children came of age...
这个奇迹赐给每人一项神奇天赋
The miracle blessed each with a magic gift to help us.
等他们的孩子到了一定年纪
And when their children came of age...
他们也得到魔法
They got magic, too.
没错
That's right!
于是我们家人的天赋
And together, our family's gifts...
共同使我们的新家成了天堂
Have made our new home a paradise.
今晚这蜡烛会赐给你天赋，小心肝
Tonight, this candle will give you your gift, mi vida.
巩固我们的小区，巩固我们家
Strengthen our community, strengthen our home.
让你的家人骄傲
Make your family proud.
让我的家人骄傲
Make my family proud.
对，屋神卡西达，我们要走了
Yes, yes, casita, we're going!
你想我的天赋会是什么呢？
What do you think my gift will be?
你是个奇迹，米拉贝儿马瑞格
You are a wonder, mirabel madrigal.
无论是什么天赋在等着
Whatever gift awaits...
都会和你一样特别
Will be just as special as you.
魔法满屋
让你的家人骄傲
Make your family proud.
早，阿公
Morning, abuelo!
喂！神奇天赋何时降临？
Hey! When's the magic gift happen?
今晚是我表弟的仪式
My cousin's ceremony is tonight.
他的天赋是什么？
What's his gift?
到时就知道了
We're gonna find out!
你的天赋是什么？
What's your gift?
谁在问？
Who's asking?
我们
Us!
「我们」，我不能谈自己
Well, "us," I can't just talk about myself. I'm only part of the amazing madrigals.
我只是神奇马瑞格家的一分子
神奇马瑞格家有谁？
Who's all the amazing madrigals?
你们就是不放过我吧？
Ah, you're not gonna leave me alone, are you?
卡西达，帮帮我
Casita, help me out.
抽屉
Drawers!
地板
Floors!
门
Doors!
开唱啰
Let's go!
这是我们家，多代同堂
This is our home we've got every generation.
充满着音乐，自己的节奏
So full of music a rhythm of its own design.
这是我的家，完美一群人
This is my family a perfect constellation.
就像是星星，人人都闪耀
So many stars and everybody gets to shine.
噢
Whoa.
但要搞清楚，阿嬷是老大
But let's be clear abuela runs this show.
噢，好多年以前，她带我们来
Whoa she led us here so many years ago.
噢，每年我们家，福气满满满
Whoa and every year our family blessings grow.
有很多事情，一定要知道
There's just a lot you simply got to know so.
欢迎光临马瑞格家族
Welcome to the family madrigal.
马瑞格的甜蜜家园
The home of the family madrigal.
我们出发了
We're on our way.
所有人既美妙又神奇
Where all the people are fantastical and magical
我是马瑞格家的一分子
I'm part of the family madrigal.
天啊，是他们 -有什么天赋？
- Oh, my gosh! It's them! - What are the gifts?
我忘了大家的天赋 -我忘了谁是谁
- I can't remember all the gifts! - But I don't know who is who.
好啦…放轻松
All right, all right, relax!
根本不可能放轻松 -通通告诉我们
- It is physically impossible to relax! - Tell us everything!
你有什么魔力？
- What are your powers? - Just tell us what everyone can do!
告诉我们每个人能做什么
所以大人才能喝咖啡
And that's why coffee's for grown-ups.
我的佩芭阿姨，心情会影响天气
My tía pepa her mood affects the weather.
当她不快乐，气温就搞怪
When she's unhappy well, the temperature gets weird.
我的布鲁诺舅舅
My tío Bruno.
我们不谈布鲁诺
We don't talk about Bruno!
据说他看见未来，有一天就消失了
They say he saw the future one day he disappeared.
那是我妈胡莉叶塔，来说说她这个人
Oh and that's my mom Julieta, here's her deal.
其实她能用一顿饭疗愈你
Whoa the truth is she can heal you with a meal.
她的美食真的有疗效
Whoa her recipes are remedies for real.
如果你觉得厉害，想象我的感受
If you're impressed imagine how I feel.
妈
Mom!
欢迎光临马瑞格家
Welcome to the family madrigal.
马瑞格的甜蜜家园
The home of the family madrigal.
借过
Hey, coming through!
我知道听来有点幻想与神奇
I know it sounds a bit fantastical and magical.
但我是马瑞格家的一分子
But I'm part of the family madrigal.
两个男生爱上了马瑞格家
- Two guys fell in love with family madrigal. - With family madrigal.
现在他们是马瑞格家的一分子
-And now they're part of the family madrigal -the family madrigal.
菲利姨丈娶佩芭，我爸娶胡莉叶塔
See, yeah, tío félix married pepa and my dad married Julieta.
所以阿嬷成为马瑞格阿嬷
-That's how abuela became an abuela madrigal -abuela madrigal.
走吧，走吧
Let's go let's go.
我们发誓永远帮助周遭的人
We swear to always help those around us.
获得上天赐予的奇迹
And earn the miracle that somehow found us.
小镇不断成长，世界不停转动
The town keeps growing the world keeps turning.
但工作和奉献将使奇迹不停歇
But work and dedication will keep the miracle burning.
每个新生代都得维系奇迹
And each new generation must keep the miracle burning.
等一下，谁是姐姐，谁是表弟？
Wait, who's the sister and who's the cousin?
好多人喔
There are so many people!
你怎么认得他们？
How do you keep them all straight?
好啦…
Okay, okay, okay.
家里好多小孩，音量催落去
So many kids in our house so, let's turn the sound up.
为什么？孙儿集合时间到了
You know why? I think it's time for a grandkid round-up!
孙儿集合
Grandkid round-up.
朵乐表姐有顺风耳
Cousin Dolores can hear a pin drop.
卡米罗会变身，安东尼奥今日得天赋
Camilo shapeshifts Antonio gets his gift today.
我姐姐伊莎贝拉和路易莎
-My older sisters Isabela and luisa -Isabela and luisa.
一个强壮一个优雅，面面都完美
One strong, one graceful perfect in every way.
伊莎贝拉 -种了花，小镇也疯狂
-Isabela -grows a flower and the town goes wild.
伊莎贝拉
Isabela.
她是完美的宝贝孩子
She's the perfect golden child.
路易莎…
Luisa, luisa.
路易莎头好壮壮
And luisa's super strong.
力与美令人激赏
The beauty and the brawn do no wrong.
快准备好 -来了，阿嬷
- Let's get ready! - Coming, abuela!
这就是马瑞格家的生活
That's life in the family madrigal.
现在你认识马瑞格家了
Now you know the family madrigal.
所有人既美妙又神奇
Where all the people are fantastical and magical.
这就是我们马瑞格家，再见
That's who we are in the family madrigal adiós.
你的天赋到底是什么？
But what's your gift?
我该走了，这就是马瑞格家的生活
Well, I gotta go the life of a madrigal.
现在你们都认识马瑞格家了
But now you all know the family madrigal.
我根本不是要自我介绍
I never meant this to get autobiographical.
只是聊聊马瑞格家，我们走
It was just to review the family madrigal let's go.
米拉贝儿呢？-从阿嬷开始
- But what about mirabel? - It starts with abuela.
然后是佩芭阿姨，她主管天气
And then tía pepa she handles the weather.
米拉贝儿呢？
But what about mirabel?
我妈胡莉叶塔用玉米饼使你身心舒畅
My mom Julieta can make you feel better with just one arepa.
米拉贝儿呢？-我爸奥古斯丁
- But what about mirabel? - My dad agustín.
他常出意外，但免惊
Well he's accident-prone but he means well.
米拉贝儿呢？
But what about mirabel?
你想了解每个人，我有姐姐和表亲
Hey you said you wanna know what everyone does, I got sisters and cousins and.
米拉贝儿
Mirabel.
卡米罗表哥绝对逗你笑
My primo Camilo won't stop until he makes you smile today.
朵乐表姐能听见远方的歌声
My cousin Dolores can hear this whole chorus a mile away.
看，是马里亚诺先生
Look it's Mr. Mariano.
如果愿意，你能娶我姐
Hey you can marry my sister if you wanna.
偷偷告诉你，她有公主病
Between you and me she's kind of a prima Donna.
我说太多了，谢谢，我该走了
Oh, I've said too much and thank you but I really gotta go.
我家人好棒棒 -米拉贝儿
-My family's amazing -mirabel.
我也是我家人 -米拉贝儿
-And I'm in my family so -mirabel.
好啰
Well.
米拉贝儿
Mirabel!
你在做什么？
What are you doing?
他们在问我们家的人…
They were just asking about the family and...
她要告诉我们她的超赞天赋
She was about to tell us about her super awesome gift!
米拉贝儿没有天赋喔
Oh, mirabel didn't get one.
你没有天赋？
You didn't get a gift?
米拉贝儿的快递
Mirabel! Delivery!
特别给你，因为你是唯一没天赋的人
I gave you the special since you're the only madrigal kid with no gift.
这叫「特别不特别」，因为你没天赋
I call it the "not special special" since you have no gift.
谢谢
Thanks.
跟安东尼奥说祝他好运
Oh, and tell Antonio good luck.
上次的天赋仪式太瞎了
The last gift ceremony was a bummer.
那是你的，没成功
Last one being yours that did not work.
如果我是你，我会很难过
If I was you, I'd be really sad.
我的小朋友，我不难过
Well, my little friend, I am not.
因为不管有没有天赋
Because the truth is, gift or no gift...
我就跟其他家人一样特别
I am just as special as the rest of my family.
谁要多一点粉红色？
Who wants more pink?
各位，我该把马车放哪里？
All right, guys, where do I drop the wagon?
也许你的天赋是不肯承认事实
Maybe your gift is being in denial.
我画出一道彩虹
I made a rainbow!
把椅子拿开
Get the chairs out of the way.
抱歉，借过
Sorry. Excuse me.
朵乐，你能听到谁会迟到吗？
Dolores, can you hear if anyone is gonna be late?
高一点，再高一点
Lift it higher. Higher.
做得不错喔 -是啊
- Hey, nice job over there. - Yeah, yeah.
卡米罗，我们还需要一个荷西
Camilo, we need another José!
荷西
José!
路易莎，钢琴搬上楼
Luisa, the piano goes upstairs!
马上办，小心，妹
I'm on it! Careful, sis!
我宝贝的这一夜必须完美，可是没有
My baby's night has to be perfect, and it's not perfect.
大家快来了
And people are going to be coming.
东西都没准备好
And nothing's ready.
鲜花
The flowers!
有人说鲜花吗？
Did someone say flowers?
伊莎贝拉
Isabela!
我们的天使…
Our angel, our angel!
请不要拍手
Please don't clap.
谢谢 -没什么
- Thank you. - Oh, it's nothing.
姐姐给你一个建议
A little sisterly advice...
不要老是那么努力，就不会碍事
If you weren't always trying too hard, you wouldn't be in the way.
其实，伊莎，这叫帮忙
Actually, isa, this is called helping.
而且我没碍事，你才是
And I'm not in the way. You are.
借过
Excuse me.
小心肝，你还好吧？不必做得这么累
Mi vida, you okay? You don't have to overdo it.
我知道，妈妈
I know, mamá.
我想尽一己之力，跟其他家人一样
I just wanna do my part like the rest of the family.
她说得对，亲爱的
She's right, amor.
在你之后的首次天赋仪式，五味杂陈
First gift ceremony since yours. A lot of emotions.
蜜蜂螫过敏 -我感同身受
- Bee stings! - And I've been there.
我和你菲利姨丈进入这个家族时
When me and your tío félix married into the family...
是没有天赋的外人，永远不会有
Outsiders who had no gift, never, ever would...
被非凡的人包围，很容易感觉…
Surrounded by the exceptional, it was easy to feel...
平凡
UN-ceptional.
好吧，爸
Okay, papi.
总之我能体会 -吃下去
- I'm just saying, I get it. - Eat.
亲爱的，如果你想谈…
Mi amor, if you ever wanna talk...
我该忙了，房子可不会自己布置
I gotta put out the stuff. The house isn't gonna decorate itself.
抱歉，你可以，你看来好棒
Sorry, you could. You look great.
乖女儿，记住 -对，别忘了
- Corazón, remember! - Yeah, remember!
你不需证明什么 -不需证明什么
- You have nothing to prove! - You have nothing to prove!
（路易莎）
（伊莎贝拉）
（阿嬷）
你们摆这里 -去打扫你们房间
- You guys can set up over here. - Clean your rooms!
我不管它们有多大
I don't care how big they are.
有人看到我的提普琴吗？
Has anybody seen my tiple?
一个小时
One hour!
糟了
No, no, no!
也许你应该让别人来布置？
Maybe you should leave the decorations to someone else?
不，我做这些是想给你一个惊喜
No, I actually made these as a surprise for you.
米拉贝儿，我知道你想帮忙
Mirabel, I know you want to help.
但今晚必须完美无缺
But tonight must go perfectly.
全镇都依靠我们家，我们的天赋
The whole town relies on our family, on our gifts.
有些人要帮忙，最好就是别碍事
So, the best way for some of us to help is to step aside.
让家里其他人发挥所长
Let the rest of the family do what they do best.
懂吗？
Okay?
嗯
Mm-hmm.
佩芭，你头上有云 -我知道，妈
- Pepa! You have a cloud! - I know, mamá.
我找不到安东尼奥，你要我怎样？
But now I can't find Antonio. What do you want from me?
妈，别对米拉贝儿太严厉
Mamá, be nice to mirabel, okay?
你也知道她今晚不好受
You know tonight will be hard for her.
如果这次天赋仪式不顺利
If the gift ceremony doesn't go well this time...
今晚我们所有人都不好受
Tonight will be hard for us all.
安东尼奥
Antonio!
大家都在找你
Everyone's looking for you.
如果你不拿，这个礼物会自动销毁
This present will self-destruct if you don't take it...
倒数三…
In three...
二…
Two...
一
One...
紧张吗？
Nervous?
没什么好担心的
You have nothing to worry about.
你会获得你的天赋，然后打开那扇门
You're gonna get your gift and open that door...
一定是有史以来最酷的
And it's gonna be the coolest ever.
我有信心
I know it.
如果不行呢？
What if it doesn't work?
在那个不可能发生的情况下
Well, in that impossible scenario...
你就和我一起待在这房间里
You'd stay here in the nursery with me.
永远永远
Forever.
你整个人都是我的
And I'd get you all to myself.
我好希望你能有一扇门
I wish you could have a door.
你知道吗？
You know what?
你不必替我担心
You don't have to worry about me...
因为我有一个超赞的家庭
'Cause I have an amazing family...
和一间超赞的房子
And an amazing house.
还有超赞的你
And an amazing you.
看到你获得特殊天赋和你的门
And seeing you get your special gift and your door...
对我来说比任何事都开心
That's gonna make me way more happy than anything.
但是，我会想念全世界最棒的室友
But, alas, I am gonna miss having the world's best roomie.
我知道你喜欢动物
I know you're an animal guy...
这是我做的，等你搬进超酷的新房间
And I made this so, when you move into your cool, new room...
随时都有东西可以抱抱
You always have something to snuggle with.
好，小家伙，准备好了吗？
All right, hombrecito, you ready?
对不起，我得再抱紧处理一次
Sorry, I got to get one more squeeze.
好啦…我们走
Okay, okay, we're going!
给你
Here you go!
西西莉亚，击掌
Cecilia, up top!
你来了
There you are.
看看你，都长大了
Look at you! All grown up.
佩芭，你会把他弄湿的
Pepi, amor, you're gonna get him all wet.
你会让你爸爸很骄傲
You are making your papa proud.
我讲话不是这样
I don't sound like that.
阿嬷说时间到了
Abuela says it's time.
我们会在你的门口等
We'll be waiting at your door.
好了，走…
Okay, okay.
好，不闹了
All right, I'm done!
50年前
Fifty years ago...
在我们最绝望的时候
In our darkest moment...
这根蜡烛赐给我们一个奇迹
This candle blessed us with a miracle.
我们家最大的荣耀
And the greatest honor of our family...
就是用我们的福气来服务心爱的小区
Has been to use our blessings to serve this beloved community.
今晚，我们再次齐聚一堂
Tonight, we come together once more...
又向光明踏出一步
As another steps into the light...
使我们骄傲
To make us proud.
我不能
I can't.
我需要你
I need you.
来吧，带你到你的门前
Come on, let's get you to your door.
（安东尼奥）
你愿用天赋来荣耀我们的奇迹吗？
Will you use your gift to honor our miracle?
你愿意为这个小区服务
Will you serve this community...
巩固我们的家吗？
And strengthen our home?
我懂你的意思
I understand you.
它们当然可以来啊
Of course they can come!
我们有一项新的天赋了
We have a new gift!
里面更大？
It's bigger on the inside?
安东尼奥！
Antonio!
你想去哪里？
You wanna go where?
太棒了 -好啦
- That was great! - Okay! All right!
真不可思议
That was amazing.
我就知道你做得到
I knew you could do it!
一个和你一样特别的天赋
A gift just as special as you.
我们来拍张照
We need a picture!
大家过来…
Everyone! Come, come, come!
这是一个美好的夜晚，完美的夜晚
It's a great night! It's a perfect night!
大家一起说
Everyone, together!
马瑞格家
La familia madrigal!
千万不要难过或生气
Don't be upset or mad at all.
千万不要后悔或悲伤
Don't feel regret or sad at all.
我仍是马瑞格家的一分子
Hey, I'm still a part of the family madrigal.
我很好，非常好
And I'm fine I am totally fine
当你们闪耀，我会站在一旁
I will stand on the side as you shine.
我不好，我不好
I'm not fine I'm not fine
我不能移动山河
I can't move the mountains
我不能让花朵绽放
I can't make flowers bloom
我不能在房间再度过一夜
I can't take another night up in my room.
等待奇迹降临
Waiting on a miracle
我无法治愈受损的身心
I can't heal what's broken.
无法控制晨雨或飓风
Can't control the morning rain or a hurricane.
无法压抑说不出看不见的痛
Can't keep down the unspoken invisible pain.
总在等待奇迹降临，奇迹
Always waiting on a miracle a miracle.
总是独自走着
Always walking alone.
总是期待更多
Always wanting for more.
彷佛还在门前，渴望发光
Like I'm still at that door longing to shine.
像你们一样闪耀
Like all of you shine.
我只需要一次改变
All I need is a change.
我只需要一个机会
All I need is a chance.
我只知道不能待在一旁，睁开你的眼
All I know is I can't stay on the side open your eyes.
睁开你的眼，睁开你的眼
Open your eyes open your eyes
我愿意移动山河
I would move the mountains.
让新的树木和花朵生长
Make new trees and flowers grow.
请让我知道何去何从
Someone please just let me know where do I go
我在等待奇迹降临，奇迹
I am waiting on a miracle a miracle.
我会治愈受损的身心
I would heal what's broken.
让这个家看见新气象
Show this family something new.
我内心是谁，我能怎么做？
Who I am inside so what can I do?
我受够了等待奇迹，所以来吧
I'm sick of waiting on a miracle so here I go.
我准备好了，来吧我准备好了
I am ready come on, I'm ready
我始终耐心、坚定、平稳
I've been patient and steadfast and steady.
祝福我，就像祢多年前祝福我们
Bless me now as you blessed us all those years ago.
赐给我们一个奇迹
When you gave us a miracle.
我期盼奇迹是否已太迟？
Am I too late for a miracle?
卡西达？
Casita?
（伊莎贝拉）
（路易莎）
来啊，阿嬷
Come on, abuela!
房子有危险，房子有危险
The house is in danger! The house is in danger!
砖瓦掉下来了，到处都有裂缝
The tiles were falling, and there were cracks everywhere.
蜡烛也差点熄灭
And the candle almost went out.
带我去看
Show me.
什么？
What?
（卡米罗）
不，那是…
No, that's...
那里本来有裂缝
The cracks were there.
到处都是
They were everywhere.
房子有问题，蜡烛…
The house was in trouble, the candle was...
阿嬷，我保证…
Abuela, I promise...
够了
That's enough.
马瑞格之家没有问题
There is nothing wrong with la casa madrigal.
魔法很强大
The magic is strong.
酒也很烈喔
And so are the drinks.
麻烦，下音乐
Please! Music!
如果全是我的想象，我怎么割伤手？
If it was all in my head, how did I cut my hand?
我绝对不会破坏属于安东尼奥的夜晚
I would never ruin Antonio's night.
你真的那么想吗？
Is that really what you think?
我认为今天对你来说非常难熬
What I think is that today was very hard for you.
那是…
That's...
我是为家里着想
I was looking out for the family.
我可能不像路易莎那样强壮
And I might not be super strong like luisa...
不像伊莎贝拉天生就那么完美
Or effortlessly perfect like senorita perfecta Isabela...
她头发连一天都没乱过，可是…
Who's never even had a bad hair day, but...
随便啦
Whatever.
我好希望你能用我的眼光看你自己
I wish you could see yourself the way I do.
你这样就很完美了
You are perfect just like this.
你跟这个家里其他人一样特别
You're just as special as anyone else in this family.
你用一块起司玉米饼就治好我的手了
You just healed my hand with an arepa con queso.
我用对女儿的爱治好你的手
I healed your hand with my love for my daughter...
她有灵巧的头脑
With her wonderful brain...
宽大的心胸，酷酷的眼镜 -别说了
- And big heart, cool glasses... - Stop!
妈妈
Mamá!
我知道我看到什么
I know what I saw.
米拉，我弟布鲁诺在这个家里迷失了
Mira, my brother Bruno lost his way in this family.
我不要你也一样
I don't want the same for you.
好好睡一觉
Get some sleep.
明天会感觉好一些
You'll feel better tomorrow.
佩德罗
Pedro.
我需要你
I need you.
我们家出现裂缝
Cracks in our casita.
如果我们家的人知道我们有多脆弱
If our family knew how vulnerable we truly are...
如果我们的奇迹渐渐消失
If our miracle is dying...
我们不能再失去我们的家了
We cannot lose our home again.
为什么会这样？
Why is this happening?
睁开我的眼睛
Open my eyes.
如果答案在这里，帮我找到它
If the answer is here, help me find it.
帮我保护我们家
Help me protect our family.
帮我挽救我们的奇迹
Help me save our miracle.
我会挽救这个奇迹
I will save the miracle.
等等，我要如何挽救奇迹？
Wait. How do I save a miracle?
先弄清楚奇迹发生什么状况
I figure out what's happening to the miracle.
我不知道
Oh, I have no idea.
但家里有一个人什么都听得见
But there is one person in this family who hears everything about everything.
如果有人知道魔法出了什么错
So, if anyone would know what's wrong with the magic...
喂
Hey!
就是她
It's her.
朵乐
Dolores, hey.
你是我最喜欢的表姐
You know, out of all my older cousins, you're, like, my favorite cousin...
我觉得和你无话不谈
So I feel like I can talk to you about anything...
所以你什么都能跟我说
Ergo you can talk to me about anything.
就像昨晚魔法的问题似乎没人担心
Like the problem with the magic last night that no one seemed to worry about...
也许你听到了我该知道的事
But maybe you heard about that maybe I should know about.
卡米罗，别为了偷懒假装你是朵乐
Camilo! Stop pretending you're Dolores so you can have seconds.
值得试一下
Worth a shot.
唯一担心魔法的人是你
The only one worried about the magic is you...
和在墙上说话的老鼠
And the rats talking in the walls.
还有路易莎，我听到她眼皮整晚在跳
And luisa, I heard her eye twitching all night.
好了
There we go.
大家到餐桌集合，快点…
Everyone, to the table! Let's go, let's go.
路易莎 -各位家人
- Luisa. - Family.
我们都很感恩安东尼奥美妙的新天赋
We are all thankful for Antonio's wonderful new gift.
我叫它们把你的座位弄暖
I told them to warm up your seat.
谢谢你，安东尼奥
Thank you, tonito.
今天我们会好好利用你的天赋
I'm sure today we'll find a way to put your blessings to good use.
路易莎，朵乐说你吓坏了
Luisa, Dolores says you're totally freaking out.
说不定你知道昨晚魔法…
Any chance you maybe know something about last night with the magic...
你知道 -米拉贝儿
- You do! - Mirabel!
如果你不能专心，我帮你 -其实…
- If you can't pay attention, I will help you. - Actually...
卡西达
Casita!
我刚刚说
As I was saying...
千万别把我们的奇迹视为理所当然
We must never take our miracle for granted...
所以今天我们要加倍努力工作
So today we will work twice as hard.
我来帮路易莎 -停
- Mm-hmm. I will help luisa. - Stop.
首先宣布一件事
First, an announcement.
我跟古兹曼家谈过
I've spoken to the guzmáns about Mariano's proposal to Isabela.
马里亚诺向伊莎贝拉求婚的事
朵乐，日子订了吗？
Dolores, do we have a date?
今晚，他想生五个宝宝
Tonight. He wants five babies.
太棒了
Wonderful!
那么好的年轻人配上完美的伊莎贝拉
Such a fine young man with our perfect Isabela...
会带来新一代的神奇福气
Will bring a new generation of magical blessings...
让我们两家更兴旺
And make both of our families stronger.
好，我们的小区都指望我们
Okay. Our community is counting on us.
马瑞格家
La familia madrigal!
路易莎…什么？
Luisa, hey. What?
抱歉 -你有毛病啊？
- Sorry. - What is your problem?
路易莎，等一下
Hey! Luisa, hold up!
路易莎，能改变河道吗？-看我的
- Luisa, can you re-route the river? - Will do.
路易莎，驴子又跑出来了 -马上办
- Luisa, the donkeys got out again. - On it.
路易莎
Luisa!
等一下
Wait a second!
你得跟我说魔法的事
You gotta tell me about the magic.
怎么回事？你在隐瞒什么？
What's going on? What are you hiding?
没有，我事情很多，你回家吧
Nothing. Just got a lot of chores, so maybe you should just go home.
路易莎，我的房子倾斜…
Luisa, my house is leaning to the...
朵乐说你眼皮在跳，但它从来不跳的
Dolores said your eye was twitching, and it never twitches.
有事情害你紧张
Something's making you nervous.
走开，你会害驴子掉下来
Hey, move. You're gonna make me drop a donkey.
路易莎，你能不能…
Luisa, will you just...
告诉我怎么回事 -没什么好说的
- Just tell me what it is. - There's nothing to tell.
你明明在担心
You're obviously worried about something.
路易莎，如果有东西在破坏魔法
Luisa, if you know what's hurting the magic...
因为你不说出来，变越来越严重
And it gets worse, 'cause you won't tell me what's wrong...
没有问题
Nothing's wrong!
抱歉
Wow, sorry.
脱口而出，我是说…
That snuck out there. What I meant was...
怎么会有问题呢？
Why would anything be wrong?
我很好，魔法没事
I'm totally fine. The magic's fine.
路易莎很好，我一点也不紧张
Luisa's fine. I'm totally not nervous.
你的眼皮又在跳了
Your eye is doing the thing...
我很强壮，我不紧张
I'm the strong one I'm not nervous
我和地壳一样强悍
I'm as tough as the crust of the earth is.
好吧
Okay.
我能移山，能搬教堂
I move mountains I move churches.
我发光发热，知道我的价值
And I glow 'cause I know what my worth is.
当然…你们要去哪？
Of course, I mean... Hey, where are you going?
我不问工作有多辛苦
I don't ask how hard the work is.
钻石与白金，表面粗糙坚硬
Got a rough, indestructible surface diamonds and platinum
我找到它们，压扁它们
I find 'em I flatten 'em
接受任务，使命必达
I take what I'm handed I break what's demanded.
但在表面下，我觉得疯狂，像走钢索
But under the surface, I feel berserk as a tightrope Walker in a three-ring circus.
在表面下，就像大力士说
Under the surface was Hercules ever like.
「我不想对抗三头犬」
"Yo, I don't wanna fight Cerberus".
在表面下
Under the surface
我确定自己没价值，若不能为人服务
I'm pretty sure I'm worthless if I can't be of service.
一个瑕疵或裂缝
A flaw or a crack.
一根稻草就能压垮骆驼
The straw in the stack that breaks the camel's back.
压垮骆驼
What breaks the camel's back?
压力就像永不停止的水滴
It's pressure like a drip, drip, drip that'll never stop.
喔
Whoa.
压力一直来直到你爆炸
Pressure that'll tip, tip, tip till you just go pop.
喔
Whoa.
交给你姐姐，你姐年纪大
Give it to your sister your sister's older.
把我们扛不住的重担交给她
Give her all the heavy things we can't shoulder.
如果不能扛起重任，我算什么？
Who am I if I can't run with the ball?
如果向压力屈服，它不肯放手
If I fall to pressure like a grip, grip, grip and it won't let go.
喔
Whoa.
压力滴答滴答，即将爆炸
Pressure like a tick, tick, tick till it's ready to blow.
喔
Whoa.
交给你姐姐，你姐年纪大
Give it to your sister your sister's stronger.
看她能不能再撑久一点
See if she can hang on a little longer.
如果不能扛起重任，我算什么？
Who am I if I can't carry it all?
如果我动摇
If I falter.
在表面下
Under the surface
我故作镇定，担心我们受伤害
I hide my nerves and it worsens I worry something is gonna hurt us.
在表面下
Under the surface.
听到巨大的冰山，船却没转向
The ship doesn't swerve as it heard how big the iceberg is.
在表面下，我想起我的目标
Under the surface I think about my purpose.
我能保护它吗？排好骨牌
Can I somehow preserve this? Line up the dominos.
一阵轻风吹过，你试图阻止它倒下
A light wind blows you try to stop it topplin'.
它开始倾倒，但等等
But on and on it goes but wait.
如果我能甩开
If I could shake.
期望惊人的重量
The crushing weight of expectations.
会不会获得喜悦
Would that free some room up for joy.
或放松的空间？
Or relaxation?
或简单的乐趣，不要去测量
Or a simple pleasure instead we measure.
不断增长的压力
This growing pressure keeps growing.
继续前进，因为我们只知道
Keep going 'cause all we know is.
压力就像永不停止的水滴
Pressure like a drip, drip, drip that'll never stop.
喔
Whoa.
压力一直来直到你爆炸
Pressure that'll tip, tip, tip till you just go pop.
喔
Whoa.
交给姐姐，它不会痛
Give it to your sister it doesn't hurt.
看她能不能处理家里每个负担
And see if she can handle every family burden.
她低身弯腰，但依然挺住
Watch as she buckles and bends but never breaks.
毫无错误
No mistakes.
如果向压力屈服，它不肯放手
Just pressure like a grip, grip, grip and it won't let go.
喔
Whoa.
压力一直来直到你爆炸
Pressure like a tick, tick, tick till it's ready to blow.
喔
Whoa.
交给姐姐，千万别怀疑
Give it to your sister and never wonder.
同样的压力是否会把你拉倒
If the same pressure would have pulled you under.
如果没有这般能耐，我算什么？
Who am I if I don't have what it takes?
没有裂缝，没有断折
No cracks no breaks.
没有错误，没有压力
No mistakes no pressure.
我觉得你负担太大了
I think you're carrying way too much...
也许我做过头了
Maybe I overdo it.
对
Yep.
有件事你应该知道
There is something you should know.
昨晚，当你看到裂缝时
Last night, when you saw the cracks...
我觉得…软弱
I felt... weak.
什么？
What?
路易莎，驴子 -看我的
- Luisa! The donkeys! - On it!
等等…什么意思？
Wait, wait, wait. What do you mean?
你想是什么在破坏魔法？
What do you think's hurting the magic?
不知道，但有一次我听到大人说
Don't know, but I heard the grown-ups once.
在布鲁诺舅舅离开前
Before tío Bruno left...
他曾看过一个可怕的幻象
He had, like, some terrible vision about it.
布鲁诺舅舅？他看到什么？
Tío Bruno? What was in his vision?
没人知道，他们始终没找到
No one knows. They never found it.
但如果魔法出问题
But if something's wrong with the magic, start with Bruno's tower.
就从布鲁诺塔开始查
去找那个幻象
Find that vision.
等等，幻象怎么找？到底该找什么？
Wait! How do you find a vision? What am I even looking for?
只要你找到，就会知道
If you find it, you'll know.
可是要小心
But be careful.
那地方不准靠近是有原因的
That place is off limits for a reason.
真是绝配
Such a perfect match.
好完美
So perfect.
对这非凡之地也很好
And so good for the encanto.
（布鲁诺）
卡西达
Casita.
你能把沙子关掉吗？
Can you turn off the sand?
你在这里帮不上忙？
You can't help in here?
我没事的
I'll be fine.
我需要这么做
I need to do this.
为了你，为了阿嬷
For you, for abuela...
有一点也是为了我
Maybe a little for me.
「找到幻象，挽救…」
"Find the vision, save the..."
（你的未来在等你）
你好
Oh, hello.
好多阶梯
Lot of stairs...
但至少我有个朋友
But at least I'll have a friend.
没了，它立马飞走
No. He flew away immediately.
好吧
All right.
欢迎光临马瑞格家
Welcome to the family madrigal.
马瑞格家阶梯好多
There's so many stairs in the casa madrigal.
你以为有别的办法爬高
You think there would be another way to get so high 'cause we're magic, but no.
因为我们有魔法，才怪
神奇的是竟有这么多阶梯
Magical how many stairs fit in here!
布鲁诺，你的房间最瞎了
Bruno, your room is the worst!
不会吧
Come on...
好，我做得到
Okay, I can do this.
胆小鬼！
Quitter!
空的
Empty.
是什么在破坏魔法？
What's hurting the magic?
我
Me.
你从哪冒出来，匆匆忙忙的？
Where are you coming from in such a hurry?
对不起，我…
I'm sorry I was...
你头发上那是什么？
What is in your hair?
我的天赋
My gift!
我失去我的天赋了 -什么？
- I'm losing my gift! - What?
米拉贝儿和我谈到我负担太多
Mirabel and I were having this little talk about me carrying too much.
我尽量不扛太多，却发现速度变慢
So, I tried not to carry so much, but I realized it was putting me behind.
我就知道我会让大家失望
And I knew I was gonna let everyone down.
我感觉好难过，就抓起所有驴子
And I felt really bad, so I was grabbing all the donkeys...
但我把驴子抛进谷仓时，它们…
But then when I went to throw the donkeys in the barn, they were...
好重
Heavy!
你做了什么？你对她说什么？
What did you do? What did you say to her?
没有，我不…
Nothing. I don't...
米拉贝儿，我得去接古家人
Mirabel, I have to go get the guzmáns for Isabela's engagement.
谈伊莎贝拉订婚的事
离路易莎远一点，等我和她谈
Stay away from luisa until I can talk to her.
今晚不能再出问题了
Tonight, we can't have any more problems.
无论你在做什么，给我停止
And whatever you're doing, stop doing it.
为何我在你的幻象中，布鲁诺？
Why am I in your vision, Bruno?
阿姨，天啊
Tía! jeez.
对不起，我不是故意…
Sorry, I didn't mean to...
出去…
Shoo, shoo, shoo!
我来拿安东尼奥剩下的东西
I just wanted to get the last of tonito's things...
然后就听到我们不说的那个名字
And then I heard the name we do not speak.
真赞，这下我打雷了，再来是毛毛雨
Great. Now I'm thundering, and that thunder will lead to a drizzle...
毛毛雨又带来小雨
And a drizzle will lead to a sprinkle...
晴朗的天空…
Clear skies, clear skies.
晴朗的天空
Clear skies.
佩芭阿姨，如果…
Tía pepa? If...
如果他看到某人的幻象，代表什么？
If he had a vision about someone, what would it mean for them?
我们不谈布鲁诺
We don't talk about Bruno.
我知道，只是假设，如果他看到你…
I know. It's just hypothetically, if he saw you...
米拉贝儿，拜托
Mirabel, please, we need to get ready for the guzmáns.
我们要准备接待古家人
我想知道是通常如此，还是不太可能
I just wanna know if it was generally positive or, like, less positive...
那是一场恶梦 -菲利
- It was a nightmare! - Félix!
她应该知道，佩芭，她应该知道
Hey, she needs to know, pepi, she needs to know.
我们不谈布鲁诺
We don't talk about Bruno.
他会看到可怕的东西，然后…
He would see something terrible. And then...
砰！会发生
Boom! It would happen.
我们不谈布鲁诺
We don't talk about Bruno.
要是你不懂他看到的呢？
What if you didn't understand what he saw?
那最好弄清楚，因为它会来找你
Then you better figure it out, because it was coming for you.
我们不谈论布鲁诺，不不不
We don't talk about Bruno-no-no-no.
我们不谈布鲁诺
We don't talk about Bruno.
那是我的大喜之日 -我们大喜之日
- But it was my wedding day. - It was our wedding day.
我们正在准备，天空万里无云
We were getting ready and there wasn't a cloud in the sky.
天空不准有云
No clouds allowed in the sky.
布鲁诺走进来，带着调皮的笑容
Bruno walks in with a mischievous grin.
打雷
Thunder.
是你在说故事还是我？
You're telling the story or am I?
对不起，亲爱的，继续
I'm sorry, mi vida go on.
布鲁诺说看来快下雨了
Bruno says it looks like rain.
他为何要告诉她？
Why did he tell her?
他害我胡思乱想
In doing so, he floods my brain.
阿嬷拿起雨伞
Abuela gets the umbrella.
在飓风中结婚
Married in a hurricane.
多欢喜的一天，但无论如何
What a joyous day but anyway.
我们不谈论布鲁诺，不不不
We don't talk about Bruno-no-no-no.
我们不谈布鲁诺
We don't talk about Bruno.
嘿
Hey.
生活中越来越怕布鲁诺
Grew to live in fear of Bruno stuttering or stumbling
我总能听到他喃喃自语
I can always hear him sort of muttering and mumbling
联想到落沙的声音
I associate him with the sound of falling sand.
有天赋却如此谦虚不容易
It's a heavy lift with a gift so humbling.
总让阿嬷和家人支支吾吾
Always left abuela and the family fumbling.
努力理解他们不懂的预言
Grappling with prophecies they couldn't understand.
你明白吗？
Do you understand?
身高超过两米，背上有老鼠
Seven-foot frame rats along his back.
当他叫你名字，又渐渐变成黑
When he calls your name it all fades to black.
他看见你的梦，你尖叫他更兴奋
Yeah, he sees your dreams and feasts on your screams.
我们不谈论布鲁诺，不不不
We don't talk about Bruno-no-no-no.
我们不谈布鲁诺
We don't talk about Bruno.
他说我的鱼会死，第二天果然成真
He told me my fish would die the next day dead.
不，不
No, no.
他说我会长出大肚腩，结果是真的
He told me I'd grow a gut and just like he said.
不，不 -他说我头发会消失
-No, no -he said that all my hair would disappear.
现在看看我的头
Now look at my head.
不，不
No, no.
当预言说出来，你命运就已注定
Your fate is sealed when your prophecy is read.
他说我梦想中的生活
He told me that the life of my dreams.
总有一天会实现
Would be promised and someday be mine.
他说我的魔力会增长
He told me that my power would grow.
就像葡萄树上茂盛的葡萄
Like the grapes that thrive on the vine.
马里亚诺出发了
Mariano's on his way.
他说我的梦中情人
He told me that the man of my dreams.
将会遥不可及
Would be just out of reach.
与别人订婚
Betrothed to another.
我彷佛听见他 -嘿，姐
- It's like I hear him now. - Hey, sis.
我不想听你说话
I want not a sound out of you.
我彷佛听见他
I can hear him now.
布鲁诺，关于那个布鲁诺
Um, Bruno yeah, about that Bruno
我真想知道布鲁诺的事
I really need to know about Bruno give me the truth and the whole truth, Bruno.
给我全部真相，布鲁诺
伊莎贝拉，你男朋友来了
Isabela, your boyfriend's here!
晚餐时间到
Time for dinner.
那是我的大喜之日 -我们大喜之日
- It was my wedding day. - It was our wedding day.
天空万里无云 -万里无云
- And there wasn't a cloud in the sky. - No clouds allowed in the sky.
（路易莎）
他说我的魔力会增长
He told me that my power would grow.
打雷 -是你在说故事还是我？
- Thunder. - You're telling the story or am I?
马里亚诺出发了
Mariano's on his way.
布鲁诺说快下雨了 -他为何告诉她
- Bruno says it looks like rain. - Why did he tell her?
他害我胡思乱想 -阿嬷拿起雨伞
- In doing so, he floods my brain. - Abuela gets the umbrella.
在飓风中结婚
Married in a hurricane.
他来了，不要谈布鲁诺
He's here don't talk about Bruno-no.
我为何谈布鲁诺？
Why did I talk about Bruno?
千万别讲布鲁诺
Not a word about Bruno
我根本不该提起布鲁诺
I never should have brought up Bruno.
米拉贝儿，准备好了吗？我…
Miraboo! Got your party pants on? 'Cause I...
我闯进布鲁诺塔
I broke into Bruno's tower.
发现他最后的幻象，我们家有麻烦
I found his last vision. The family's in trouble.
魔法快没了，房子快倒了
The magic is dying. The house is breaking, luisa's gift is fading.
路易莎的天赋逐渐消失
我想一切都是因为我？
And I think it's all because of me?
爸？
Pá?
什么都别说，阿嬷希望今晚完美无瑕
We say nothing. Abuela wants tonight to be perfect.
古家人离开前别说你闯进布鲁诺塔
Until the guzmáns leave, you did not break into Bruno's tower.
魔法还在，房子没坏
The magic is not dying. The house is not breaking.
路易莎的天赋没消失
Luisa's gift is not fading.
没人会知道的，装没事
No one will know. Just act normal.
谁都不必知道
No one has to know.
我知道
I know.
她会告诉所有人
She's gonna tell everyone.
吃饭啰
Time to eat!
古兹曼家和马瑞格家结亲一定旺
The guzmáns and the madrigals together will be so good for the encanto.
对，希望今晚不是可怕的灾难
Yes. Then, let's hope tonight is not a horrible disaster.
敬完美的夜晚
To a perfect night!
酪梨？
Avocado?
卡米罗，脸调整一下
Camilo. Fix your face.
喝水？
Water?
米拉贝儿
Mirabel.
请给我鲜奶油
The cream, please?
爸，鲜奶油？
Pá, the cream?
布鲁诺的幻象
Bruno's vision.
佩芭，有云
Pepa, the cloud.
晴朗的天空…
Clear skies, clear skies, clear skies.
布鲁诺的幻象
Bruno's vision.
米拉贝儿
Mirabel?
一切都还好吗？
Everything okay?
都很好，她只是很兴奋
Everything is great. She's just excited.
因为你要求婚，该求婚了
For you to propose. Which you should do!
对 -尽快
- Yes. - As fast as you can.
其实我本来要…
I was actually gonna...
其实你本来要，太好了
You were actually gonna. Great!
既然这里每个人都有天赋
Well, since everyone here has a talent...
我的马里亚诺想先唱首歌
My Mariano wanted to begin with a song!
路易莎，你能把钢琴搬过来吗？
Luisa, could you bring over the piano?
好吧
Okay.
我们家的传统是事后才唱
It's actually family tradition to sing after.
伊莎贝拉，最优雅的马瑞格家人
Isabela, most graceful of all the madrigals.
你表现得很好
You're doing great.
整个非凡之地最完美的花…
The most perfect flower in this entire encanto...
不
No!
在整个非凡之地…
你愿意嫁给…
Will you marry...
不！
No!
怎么回事？
What is happening?
米拉贝儿发现布鲁诺幻象，她在里面
Mirabel found Bruno's vision. She's in it.
她会破坏魔法，我们完蛋了
She's gonna destroy the magic and now, we're all doomed!
阿嬷，拜托，这一定有原因
Abuela, please! There's gotta be an explanation.
我恨你
I hate you!
我是个鲁蛇 -路易莎
- I'm a loser! - Luisa!
你做了什么？
What did you do?
我什么都没做，是布鲁诺的幻象
I'm not doing anything! It's Bruno's vision!
魔法很强，一切都很好
The magic is strong! Everything is fine!
我们是马瑞格家
We are the madrigals!
米拉贝儿
Mirabel!
喂
Hey!
没事，深吸一口气，吐气
It's okay, mami. Deep breath in, deep breath out.
别跑
Stop!
不！不！
No! No!
救命啊…
Help! Help...
卡西达…
Casita! Casita!
救救我
Help me!
你满身大汗
You're very sweaty.
糟糕
Oh, no!
掰 -什么？
- Bye. - What?
不，等等
No. Hold on!
等一下
Wait! Wait!
你为什么会有这个幻象？
Why did you take the vision?
敲敲敲…求好运
Knock, knock, knock, knock, knock. Knock on wood.
它代表什么？
What does it mean?
这是你回来的原因还是…
Is it why you came back or...?
布鲁诺舅舅？
Tío Bruno?
敲敲敲…求好运
Knock, knock, knock, knock, knock. Knock on wood.
你根本不该看见那个幻象，谁都不该
You were never supposed to see that vision. No one was.
但是… -一点盐
- But... - A little salt.
糖
Sugar.
等等
Wait.
你都在这里修补裂缝吗？
Have you been in here patching the cracks?
那个？没有…我太害怕不敢靠近
Oh, that? No, no, no. I'm too scared to go near those things.
都是赫南多修补的
All the patching's done by hernando.
赫南多是谁？
- Who is hernando? - I'm hernando and I'm scared of nothing!
我是赫南多，天不怕地不怕
其实就是我
It's actually me.
我常说我真正的天赋是「演戏」
I used to say my real gift was "acting."
我是荷黑，会填泥料
I'm Jorge. I make the spackle.
你在这里待多久了？
How long have you been back here?
你没离开过
You never left.
我离开我的塔，那里有很多阶梯
Well, I left my tower, which was, you know, a lot of stairs...
在这里，厨房超近
And here, kitchen adjacent.
还有免费的娱乐
Plus, free entertainment.
你喜欢什么？喜欢运动吗？
So, what do you like? You like sports?
游戏节目？肥皂剧？
Game shows? Telenovelas?
他们的爱太感人了
Their love could never be.
我不懂
I don't understand.
因为她是他姑姑，她有失忆症
Well, because she's his aunt and she has amnesia...
所以不记得她是他姑姑
So she can't remember that she's his aunt.
这是一种非常禁忌的…
It's like a very forbidden kind of...
我不明白你为何离开了又没离开
I don't understand why you left, but didn't leave.
因为我们家周围都是高山
Oh, well, because, the mountains around the encanto are pretty tall.
就像我说的，有免费食物
And like I said, free food and everything.
你们喜欢免费食物，对不对？
You guys love the free food, don't ya?
永远吃不饱
Always hungry. Never satisfied.
（布鲁诺）
我的天赋没有帮助家里
My gift wasn't helping the family...
但我爱我的家人
But, I love my family, you know?
我只是不知道如何…
I just don't know how to...
总之你该走了，因为…
Well, anyway, I think you should go, because...
没什么好理由，如果有，你会说
I don't really have a good reason, but, if I did, you'd be like...
「我该走了，因为这是好理由」
"I should go, because that's a good reason."
为什么我在你的幻象里？
Why was I in your vision?
布鲁诺舅舅
Tío Bruno?
我只想让家人为我骄傲
I just wanted to make the family proud of me.
一次就好
Just once.
但如果我该停止
But if I should stop...
如果我伤害了家人
If I'm hurting my family...
尽管告诉我
Just tell me.
我不能告诉你
I can't tell you...
因为我不知道
Because I don't know.
你没获得天赋那晚，我看见这个幻象
I had this vision the night that you didn't get your gift.
阿嬷很担心魔法
Abuela worried about the magic.
她求我预见未来，看它代表什么
So, she begged me to look into the future. See what it meant.
我看到魔法陷入危险
And I saw the magic in danger.
我们的房子瓦解
Our house breaking.
然后…我看到你
And then, and then, and then, I saw you.
但这个幻象不同，它会改变
But the vision was different. It would change.
而且没有一个答案，没有明确的命运
And there was no one answer. No clear fate.
好像你的未来悬而未决
Like your future was undecided.
但我知道大家会怎么想
But I knew how it was gonna look. I knew what everyone would think...
因为我是布鲁诺，大家总往坏处想
Because I'm Bruno and everyone always assumes the worst, so...
所以…
So...
你离开是为了保护我？
You left to protect me?
我不知道情况会怎么发展
I don't know which way it'll go...
但我猜…
But my guess...
我们家，非凡之地
The family, the encanto...
还有奇迹本身的命运
And the fate of the miracle itself...
终究会靠你来决定
Well, it's all gonna come down to you.
也许我错了
Or maybe I'm wrong.
这是个谜，所以我的幻象…
You know, it's a mystery. That's why this vision is...
如果还能帮忙，我愿意
Look, if I could help anymore, I would...
但我只知道这么多
But that's all I know.
祝你好运，真希望我能看到更多
Good luck. I wish I could've seen more.
是啊
Yeah.
你希望你能看到更多，那就看更多
You wish you could have seen more, so see more!
再来另一个幻象
Have another vision.
不，我已经不产生幻象了
No, no. See, I don't do visions anymore.
但你可以 -我不愿意
- But you could. - But I won't.
你不能说世界的重担都在你的肩上
You can't say the weight of the world is on your shoulders. The end.
如果命运操之在我，那就再来个幻象
If our fate's up to me, me says have another vision.
也许它会指引我
Maybe it'll show me what to do.
即使我想，其实我不想
Look, even if I wanted to, which I don't, you wrecked my vision cave.
你也毁了我的幻象洞穴
那会是问题，因为我需要开阔大空间
Which is a problem, 'cause I need a big open space.
我们去找一个 -哪里？
- We'll find one. - Where?
用我的房间
Use my room.
老鼠把一切都告诉我了，别吃
The rats told me everything. Don't eat those.
我们家需要帮助，你需要离开这里
Our family needs help, and you need to get outta here.
你看见幻象时就该告诉我
You should have told me the second you saw the vision.
想想这个家
Think of the family.
我想的是我女儿
I was thinking of my daughter.
佩芭，冷静点
Pepa, calm down.
我在努力 -对
- I'm doing my best. - Yes.
算你好运，这不是飓风
You're lucky it's not a hurricane.
妈妈，你一直对米拉贝儿太严厉
Mamá, you've always been too hard on mirabel.
你看看
Look around.
我们必须保护家人，非凡之地
We must protect our family, our e ncanto. We cannot lose our home.
不能失去我们的家
镇上的人对魔法开始感到焦虑
People in town are becoming anxious about the magic.
他们想见你
They want to see you.
米拉贝儿出现在幻象中是有原因的
Mirabel was in that vision for a reason.
去找她
Find her.
我们可能要快点
We might wanna hurry.
未来是催不得的
You can't hurry the future.
要是我给你看到更糟的呢？
What if I show you something worse?
如果我看到你不喜欢的事，你会说
If I see something that you don't like, you're gonna be all...
布鲁诺让坏事发生，他好诡异
"Bruno makes bad things happen. Oh, he's creepy and his vision killed my goldfish."
他的幻象害死我的金鱼
我不认为你会让坏事发生
I don't think you make bad things happen.
有时家里的怪咖只是名声不好
Sometimes family weirdos just get a bad rap.
你可以做得到
You can do this.
免得你紧张
For the nerves.
我做得到…
I can do this. I can do this, I can do this, I can do this.
（布鲁诺）
你可能得抓紧
You might wanna hang on.
还是一样，我得停下来
It's just the same thing. I gotta stop!
不，我得知道怎么发展，一定有答案
No. I need to know which way it goes. There's gotta be an answer.
我们没看到的关键
Something we're not seeing!
你看到的跟我一样
You're looking at the same thing that I am.
如果还有别的… -那里
- If there was something else... - There!
在那边
Over there!
蝴蝶
Butterfly!
跟着蝴蝶走
Follow the butterfly!
那是哪里？
Where is that?
全都乱了
It's all out of order.
是那根蜡烛，越来越亮了
It's the candle. The candle's getting brighter!
我想你会帮助那根蜡烛 -怎么帮？
- I think you're gonna help the candle! - How?
有人跟你在一起
There's someone with you.
你和她打架 -什么？
- And you fight her! - What?
不，那是拥抱吗？
Wait, no, no. Is that a hug?
我是在打架还是拥抱？
Am I fighting or hugging?
拥抱…
An embrace. An embrace!
为了使蜡烛发亮，你必须拥抱她
To make the candle bright you have to embrace her.
拥抱谁？
Embrace who?
快看到了
Almost there.
是谁？-快看到了
- Who is it? - Almost there.
有了
I got it!
伊莎贝拉？
Isabela?
你姐？太好了
Your sister? That's great!
每次都这样
Every time.
拥抱伊莎贝拉怎么会有用？
Why would embracing Isabela do anything?
不知道，我们家有个奇迹
I don't know. Our family got a miracle. How do you help a family miracle?
如何帮助家庭奇迹？
拥抱一个姐妹
You hug a sister.
米拉贝儿…
Mirabel? Mirabel?
米拉贝儿
Mirabel?
我觉得我们快没时间了
Well, I think we're running out of time here.
这是行不通的
It's not gonna work.
她根本不会拥抱我，她恨我
She won't hug me ever, okay? She hates me!
你有没有听说我毁了她的求婚过程
Also, I don't know if you heard, I ruined her proposal!
而且，她超烦人的 -米拉贝儿
- Plus, p.S., she is just annoying. - Mirabel?
当然是伊莎贝拉 -米拉贝儿
- Of course it's Isabela! - Mirabel?
她对我到底有什么意见？
What's her problem with me anyway?
她让玫瑰从…
She's the one with roses coming out of her...
米拉贝儿
Mirabel!
对不起…
Sorry, sorry, sorry.
你搞错重点了
You see, you're missing the point.
我们家的命运不是由她决定
The fate of the family, it's not up to her.
而是取决于你
It's up to you.
你正是这个家需要的
You're exactly what this family needs.
你必须明白这点
You just have to see it.
自己去，我先离开
By yourself, after I leave.
什么，你不一起来吗？
What, you're not coming?
那是你的幻象，不是我的
It was your vision, mirabel. Not mine.
你怕阿嬷会见到你
You're afraid abuela will see you.
对，也是
Yep. I mean, yes, that too.
等你挽救了奇迹之后再来找我
Hey, after you save the miracle, come visit.
等我挽救奇迹之后，我要带你回家
After I save the miracle, I'm bringing you home.
敲敲敲…求好运
Knock, knock, knock, knock, knock. Knock on wood.
你可以的，只要挽救奇迹
You got this. Just gonna save the miracle.
用一个拥抱
With a hug.
伊莎？嘿
Isa? Hey.
我知道我们有点问题
I know we've had our issues...
但我准备当个更好的妹妹了
But I'm ready to be a better sister... To you.
所以我们应该拥抱一下
So, we should just hug.
一抱泯恩仇
Let's hug it out, huh?
一抱泯恩仇？
"Hug it out"?
路易莎手无缚鸡之力
Luisa can't lift an empanada...
马里亚诺鼻子像木瓜泥
Mariano's nose looks like a smashed papaya!
你疯了吗？
Have you lost your mind?
伊莎，我觉得你很生气
Isa, I feel like you're upset.
怎样才能消气呢？一个温暖的拥抱
And you know what cures being upset? A warm embrace.
出去
Get out.
本来一切都很完美
Everything was perfect.
阿嬷很开心，家人很开心
Abuela was happy. The family was happy.
你想当更好的妹妹？
You wanna be a better sister? Apologize for ruining my life.
那就为毁了我的人生道歉
快啊，道歉
Go on. Apologize.
我…
I...
很…
Am...
抱歉
Sorry...
你的人生好棒棒 -出去
- That your life is so great! - Out.
等等，好啦，我道歉
Wait! Fine! I apologize!
我并不想毁了你的人生
I wasn't trying to ruin your life!
我们有的人问题更大
Some of us have bigger problems...
你这个自私、傲慢的公主
You selfish, entitled Princess!
自私？
"Selfish"?
我一辈子都只能完美
I've been stuck being perfect my whole entire life!
可是，你成天只会帮我搞破坏
And literally, the only thing you have ever done for me is mess things up!
才没有，你还是能嫁给那个大蠢蛋
Nothing is messed up! You can still marry that big dumb hunk!
我根本不想嫁给他，我是为了这个家
I never wanted to marry him! I was doing it for the family!
我的天啊
Oh, my gosh.
伊莎
Isa...
坦承这一点很不容易
That is a very serious confession.
好，过来
Okay, get over here.
过来抱抱
Bring it in.
伊莎
Isa?
我做了一样意想不到的东西
I just made something unexpected.
很激烈，很新奇
Something sharp something new.
伊莎，这时我们应该…
Isa? This is the part where we...
它不对称也不完美，却很漂亮
It's not symmetrical or perfect but it's beautiful.
它是我的，我还能做什么？
And it's mine what else can I do?
等等，抱一下
Wait bring it in, bring it in.
很好，抱一下 -我还能做什么？
- Good talk, bring it in, bring it in. - What else can I do?
抱一下抱一下
Let's hug bring it in, bring it in.
免费拥抱，抱一下
Free hugs bring it in, bring it in
我种下一排排的玫瑰
I grow rows and rows of roses.
绵延不绝的五月花
Flor de Mayo by the mile
我摆出练习过的完美姿势
I make perfect, practiced poses.
微笑背后藏了许多辛酸
So much hides behind my smile.
如果此刻的感受滋长，我能做什么？
What could I do if I just grew what I was feeling in the moment?
你知道何去何从吗？
Do you know where you're going?
如果我知道不需完美，我能做什么？
What could I do if I just knew it didn't need to be perfect?
它只需要存在，它们让我自在
It just needed to be and they let me be.
狂风般的蓝花楹
A hurricane of jacarandás.
交缠的无花果，垂挂的藤蔓
-Strangling figs, hanging vines -fig!
这样很好
This is fine.
当我往上爬，蜡棕榈弥漫空气中
Palma de cera fills the air as I climb and I push through.
我还能做什么？
What else can I do?
我能创造一条毛毡苔之河吗？
Can I deliver us a river of sundew?
小心，这是食肉植物，一点点不够
Careful, it's carnivorous a little just won't do
我要感受新事物的悸动
I wanna feel the shiver of something new.
我厌倦了漂亮，想要真实的东西
I'm so sick of pretty I want something true, don't you?
你彷佛一睁开双眼，人生就是场梦
You just seemed like your life's been a dream since the moment you opened your eyes.
这些根向下扎得多深？
How far do these roots go down?
我只知道你种的花朵
All I know are the blossoms you grow.
但看你跃起真美妙
But it's awesome to see how you rise.
我能跳多远？-你能跳多远？
- How far can I rise? - How far can you rise?
穿过屋顶到天空，我们走
Through the roof to the skies let's go.
狂风般的蓝花楹
A hurricane of jacarandás.
交缠的无花果 -走吧
-Strangling figs -go.
垂挂的藤蔓 -成长
-Hanging vines -grow.
当我往上爬，蜡棕榈弥漫空气中
Palma de cera fills the air as I climb and I push through.
还有什么？还有什么？
What else? What else?
当你深深陷在这一刻，你能怎么做？
What can you do when you are deeply madly truly in the moment?
把握当下，继续前进
Seize the moment keep going.
当你知道目标不完美，你能怎么做？
What can you do when you know who you want to be isn't perfect?
但我还是没事 -大家让开
- But I'll still be okay. - Hey, everybody clear the way
我要穿过风铃木 -风铃木
- I'm coming through with tabebuia. - Tabebuia.
制造波浪 -制造波浪
-Making waves -making waves.
改变心意 -你改变了我
-Changing minds -you've changed mine.
因为你在，方向更清晰
The way is clearer 'cause you're here.
这一切都要感谢你
And well, I owe this all to you.
我还能做什么？
What else can I do?
让他们看看你的能耐
Show them what you can do.
我还能做什么？-没你做不到的事
- What else can I do? - There's nothing you can't do.
我还能做什么？
What else can I do?
我被你带坏了
You're a bad influence.
这是怎么回事？
What is going on?
阿嬷？没关系，一切…
Abuela? It's okay! Everything's...
我们要挽救奇迹，魔法…
We're gonna save the miracle. The magic...
你在说什么？
What are you talking about?
看看我们家，看看你姐
Look at our home! Look at your sister!
拜托…伊莎贝拉不快乐
Please just... Isabela wasn't happy.
她当然不快乐，你毁了她的求婚
Of course she isn't happy. You ruined her proposal.
不…她需要我毁掉她的求婚
No, no, no. She needed me to ruin her proposal.
然后我们做了这一切
And then we did all this!
蜡烛烧得更亮，裂缝…
And the candle burned brighter and the cracks...
米拉贝儿 -所以我才会在幻象中
- Mirabel. - That's why I'm in the vision!
我在挽救奇迹
I'm saving the miracle!
你必须停止，米拉贝儿
You have to stop, mirabel!
裂缝是从你开始的
The cracks started with you.
布鲁诺因为你才离开
Bruno left because of you.
路易莎失去魔力，伊莎贝拉失控
Luisa's losing her powers. Isabela's out of control.
都是因为你
Because of you!
我不知道你为什么没有天赋
I don't know why you weren't given a gift...
但它不是你伤害这个家的借口
But it is not an excuse for you to hurt this family.
对你来说我永远都不够好
I will never be good enough for you.
对不对？
Will I?
不管我多努力
No matter how hard I try.
无论我们有多努力
No matter how hard any of us tries.
路易莎永远不够强壮
Luisa will never be strong enough.
伊莎贝拉不够完美
Isabela won't be perfect enough.
布鲁诺离开是因为你只看到他的缺点
Bruno left our family because you only saw the worst in him.
布鲁诺不在乎这个家
Bruno didn't care about this family.
他爱这个家
He loves this family.
我爱这个家，我们都爱这个家
I love this family. We all love this family.
不在乎的人是你
You're the one that doesn't care.
破坏我们家的人是你 -不准你…
- You're the one breaking our home. - Don't you ever...
奇迹快消失都是因为你
The miracle is dying, because of you.
不…
No, no, no!
蜡烛
The candle!
卡西达，带我上去
Casita! Get me up there!
不！
No!
（安东尼奥）
小心，安东尼奥
Careful, Antonio!
我们得离开这里
We gotta get out of here!
米拉贝儿…
Mirabel! Mirabel!
米拉贝儿，快出去
Mirabel, we have to get out!
米拉贝儿 -米拉贝儿
- Mirabel! - Mirabel!
米拉贝儿，别管了
Mirabel, leave it!
米拉贝儿，房子要垮了
Mirabel! The house is going to fall!
米拉贝儿，快出来 -米拉贝儿
- Mirabel, get out! - Mirabel!
不
No.
米拉贝儿
Mirabel!
米拉贝儿，你受伤了吗？
Mirabel, are you hurt?
米拉贝儿
Mirabel!
胡莉叶塔，快来
Julieta, come quick!
胡莉叶塔
Julieta!
不要动，我马上回来
Don't move. I'll be right back.
怎么会这样？-拜托来帮忙
How did this happen?
我帮你…
Here, let me help you. Let me help you.
大家没事吧？-安东尼奥，别哭
- Everyone okay? - Antonio, don't cry, papito.
我想保护它却不行 -非凡之地毁了
How is this possible? The encanto's broken.
现在怎么办？
What do we do now?
我的魔力，消失了
My powers. They're gone.
安东尼奥呢？他要怎么办？
What about Antonio? What is he gonna do?
米拉贝儿？
Mirabel?
米拉贝儿，米拉贝儿在哪里？
Mirabel! Where's mirabel?
她在哪里？
Where is she?
米拉贝儿
Mirabel!
米拉贝儿？
Mirabel?
米拉贝儿
Mirabel!
Mirabel?
米拉贝儿
Mirabel!
他们还没找到她吗？
They haven't found her yet?
米拉贝儿 -米拉贝儿
- Mirabel! - Mirabel!
米拉贝儿
Mirabel!
Mirabel.
对不起
I'm sorry.
我并不想伤害大家
I didn't want to hurt us.
我只想…
I just wanted...
跟原来的自己不一样
To be something I'm not.
我始终无法回来这里
I've never been able to come back here.
这条河是我们奇迹降临的地方
This river is where we were given our miracle.
也就是佩德罗阿公…
Where abuelo Pedro...
我以为我们的生活会不一样
I thought we would have a different life.
我以为我会改头换面
I thought I would be a different woman.
我获得一个奇迹
I was given a miracle.
第二次机会
A second chance.
我好害怕失去它
And I was so afraid to lose it...
忘了我们奇迹的初衷
That I lost sight of who our miracle was for.
我好抱歉
And I am so sorry.
你从来没伤害过我们家，米拉贝儿
You never hurt our family, mirabel.
我们家庭破碎
We are broken...
是因为我
Because of me.
阿嬷
Abuela.
我终于明白了
I can finally see.
你失去了你的家
You lost your home.
失去了一切
Lost everything.
你吃了那么多苦
You suffered so much...
孤单无助
All alone...
那种情况才不会再发生
So it would never happen again.
我们是因为你才得救
We were saved because of you.
我们是因为你才获得奇迹
We were given a miracle, because of you.
我们是因为你才成为一个家
We are a family, because of you.
无论碰上任何困难
And nothing could ever be broken
我们都能一起解决
that we can't fix... together.
我向我的佩德罗求助
I asked my Pedro for help.
米拉贝儿
Mirabel.
结果他派你来给我
He sent me you.
不是她做的
She didn't do this!
我给了她一个幻象
I gave her a vision!
是我
It was me!
我说「去吧」，她就…
I was, like, "go!" And she was, like...
她只是想帮忙
She only wanted to help.
我不管你怎么看我，如果你太顽固…
I don't care what you think of me, but if you're too stubborn to...
Brunito.
我好像漏掉了什么重点
I feel like I missed something important.
走吧
Come on.
现在是怎样？我们要去哪？
What's happening? Where are we going?
回家
Home.
是她，我发现她了
It's her! I found her!
是我发现她的
I found her!
她回来了…
She's back! She's back, she's back!
米拉贝儿
Mirabel!
妈妈
Mamá.
亲爱的，我担心死了
Mi amor, I was so worried.
我们找不到你
We couldn't find you.
到处都是蜜蜂
There were bees everywhere.
我不会有事的
I'll be okay.
要有房子才行
Not if we don't have a house.
怎样？我们没房子啊，不能说吗？
What? We don't have a house. I can't say we don't have a house?
那是什么？不是房子
What is that? Not a house.
看看这个家，我们需要新的基础
Look at this home we need a new foundation.
看似绝望，但我们会撑过去
It may seem hopeless but we'll get by just fine.
看看这个家，闪闪发亮的一群人
Look at this family a glowing constellation.
宛如星星，每个人都想闪耀
So full of stars and everybody wants to shine.
但星星不会发光，而是燃烧
But the stars don't shine, they burn.
群星也会变换
And the constellations shift.
你该体认到
I think it's time you learn.
你的天赋无法代表你
You're more than just your gift.
抱歉我一直逼得太紧
And I'm sorry I held on too tight.
我好怕也失去你们
Just so afraid I'd lose you too.
奇迹不是你拥有的魔法
The miracle is not some magic that you've got.
奇迹就是你
The miracle is you.
不是某种天赋，就是你
Not some gift just you.
奇迹就是你
The miracle is you.
你们所有人…
All of you all of you.
好吧，我们要谈布鲁诺吗？
Okay so we gonna talk about Bruno?
那是布鲁诺？
That's Bruno?
是啊，布鲁诺有很多事能说
Yeah there's a lot to say about Bruno
我先开始，佩芭，对你的婚礼很抱歉
I'll start, okay pepa, I'm sorry about your wedding.
我不是故意要恶整
Didn't mean to be upsetting.
那不是预言，我能看到你在冒汗
That wasn't a prophecy I could just see you were sweating.
我要你知道，你哥很爱你
And I wanted you to know that your bro loves you so.
让它进，让它出，让它下雨下雪
Let it in, let it out let it rain, let it snow.
让它过去吧
Let it go.
我也这么说，哥
That's what I'm always saying, bro
我有很多事要道歉
I got a lot of apologies I got to say.
我们很高兴你回来，懂吗？
Hey, we're just happy that you're here, okay?
进入光明 -行程只有一夜
- Come into the light. - That trip was only a night.
无论如何，我们都会找到方向
And no matter what happens we're gonna find our way.
我知道他没离开，每天都听到他
Yo, I knew he never left I heard him every day.
那是什么声音？
What's that sound?
我想是镇上的所有人
I think it's everyone in town.
嘿
Hey.
放下你的负担，放下你的负担
Lay down your load lay down your load.
让我往前走，让我往前走
Roll me down the road roll me down the road.
我们没有天赋，但人数众多
We have no gifts but we are many.
愿意为你们竭尽心力
And we'll do anything for you.
当我们团队合作就是梦想，你好强壮
It's a dream when we work as a team you're so strong.
但有时我也会哭 -我也是
-Yeah, but sometimes I cry -so do I
我可能不再那么强壮，但却更聪明
I may not be as strong but I'm getting wiser.
我需要阳光与肥料
Yeah, I need sunlight and fertilizer.
来吧，种下新生命，让它成长
Come on let's plant something new and watch it fly.
直上天际
Straight up to the sky.
我们开始吧
Let's go.
星星不会发光，而是燃烧
The stars don't shine, they burn.
群星闪耀
The constellations glow.
季节更迭
The seasons change in turn.
你看我们小女儿的表现
Would you watch our little girl go.
她就像你
She takes after you.
马里亚诺，为何这么忧郁？
Hey, Mariano why so blue?
我心中有好多爱
I just have so much love inside.
我还有一个表姐，你见过朵乐吗？
You know, I've got this cousin too have you met Dolores?
我自己来，再见
Okay, I'll take it from here. Goodbye!
你说话好大声
You talk so loud.
你照顾母亲，让她骄傲
You take care of your mother and you make her proud.
每晚睡前，你自己写诗
You write your own poetry every night when you go to sleep.
我想把握时机，你醒来会注意我吗？
And I'm seizing the moment so would you wake up and notice me
朵乐，我看见你
Dolores, I see you.
我听到了你
And I hear you.
赞
Yes!
你们所有人，你们所有人
All of you all of you.
我们结婚吧 -急什么？
- Let's get married. - Slow down.
你们所有人，你们所有人
All of you all of you.
甜蜜的家，我喜欢这新的基础
Home sweet home I like the new foundation.
它并不完美
It isn't perfect.
我们也一样 -没错
-Neither are we -that's true.
在庆祝之前，还有一件事
Just one more thing before the celebration.
什么？-我们需要一个门把
- What? - We need a doorknob.
我们为你做的
We made this one for you.
我们看到你燃烧得多么亮
We see how bright you burn.
我们看到你有多么勇敢
We see how brave you've been.
现在你看看自己
Now see yourself in turn.
你是真正的天赋，孩子，让我们进去
You're the real gift, kid let us in.
睁开你的眼睛
Open your eyes.
你看到了什么？
What do you see?
我看到…我
I see... me.
全部的我
All of me.
快点，进来吧
Come on! Get in here!
耶！
Yeah!
赞啊，亲爱的
Yeah, amor!
大家一起…
Everyone, together...
马瑞格家
La familia madrigal!